VALERIE A. STIRM 4 Marshall Drive Egg Harbor Township, NJ 08234 C (609)-385-8489 vstirm@rcsj.edu

EDUCATION

Master of Arts Degree in Business/Psychology. The College of New Jersey

- * Awarded Graduate Assistantship (scholarship) in the School of Business.
- * Majored in Business Education/Psychology
- * Financed 100% tuition through assistantship.

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology/Business. The College of New Jersey

- * Majored in Psychology/Business Management minor.
- * Conducted research and study on Visual/Cognitive Perception.

Certification in Training/Development, The College of New Jersey

- *Corporate trainer for IBM.
- *Helped develop training program for introducing computers and word processing.

PROFILE

Innovative educator skilled in building positive rapport with students and colleagues. Experienced in teaching at the college level and in the corporate environment. Detail-minded problem solver. Proficient in editing, designing, and implementing course and training programs focused on assisting students to recognize their ability to succeed. Codeveloped, wrote, and taught training program on the use of the computer and word processing software applications. Highly organized with excellent interpersonal and written communication skills with more than nine years of demonstrated instructional expertise. Experience working with multicultural environments.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Corporate Trainer/Facilitator: Trained various corporate groups (Comcast, Amersource-Bergen, GCC Chamber of Commerce, and IBM) in Customer Service, Email etiquette," It's the Law: The Legal Side of Management. Thorough knowledge of computers, keyboarding and word processing applications. Work-Force: Microsoft Office 2007 – 2016, applications-Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Access. Outlook and Gmail.

Training Software Experience: Training—Velsoft, *Soft Skills Courseware*/Customer Service/E-Mail etiquette, VisionPoint Courseware/It's The Law: The Legal Side of Management, Inscapes DiSC Personal Development Profile. Other—Microsoft Office, Word, PowerPoint, Excel, and Access applications.

Professor/Advisor (Senior Adjunct): Demonstrated talent for motivating, encouraging, and leading students in a positive direction for better learning. Supervised, monitored, and taught in a classroom setting in colleges and offsite locations, as well as, Work-Force, One Stop and Behavioral Health clientele. Devised and designed Course Outline and Syllabus for departmental use.

Management - Assumed managerial responsibilities including recruiting and training personnel, scheduling and payroll control, opening and closing procedures. Experience in all aspects of banquet service, setup, and functions.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rowen College South Jersey Cumberland Campus Vineland, NJ **Adjunct Professor**

9/1/2009-Present

Atlantic Cape Community College Mays Landing, NJ **Adjunct Professor**

9/2006-Present

Atlantic Cape Community College Continuing Education Mays Landing, Hamilton, and Cape May Courthouse Campuses,

Trainer— Career Development, MS Office Suite 2007, 2010, 2016, 2019, Business English

8/2009-Present

Camden County College, Office of Customized Training, Cherry Hill, NJ Training Facilitator

3/2011-2012 9/2006-8/2007

- MS Office Suite 2007 2016
- Service Essentials: Trained corporate staff in the area of Customer Service and Conflict Management.
- Inscapes DiSC Personal Development Profile

Rutgers University, University Partnerships, Rutgers Camden Campus, NJ

2008-Present

Online Advisor—Customer Service and Call Center Management Certification, MS Office 2013

 $\textbf{Fairleigh Dickinson University}, \textbf{University Partnerships, Mays} \ \texttt{Landing}, \ \texttt{NJ}$

9/2006-9/2010

Adjunct Professor—E-Commerce, Management Information Systems, Organizational Behavior

Gloucester County College, Business and Industry Training Center, Deptford, NJ Training Consultant

8/2007-2/2008

- Velsoft Courseware: Trained corporate staff in the area of Customer Service and E-mail etiquette.
- VisionPoint Courseware: Trained corporate staff in the area of "The Legal Side of Management".

Valerie A. Stirm vstirm@rcsj.edu

Training Software and Courses Qualifications

Training Software Experience

• Velsoft, Soft Skills Courseware and Customized

- Customer Service Training, Critical Elements of Customer Service
 - What is Customer Service
 - Who Are Your Customers
 - Meeting Expectations and Service beyond Expectations
 - First Impressions
 - Setting Goals and Targets
 - Communication Active Listening
 - Telephone Techniques
 - Dealing With Conflict
 - Steps to Customer Problem Solving
 - The Recovery Process
 - Service is a Team Effort
 - Managing the Talkative Caller
 - Dealing With Difficult Caller

➤ E-Mail etiquette,

• VisionPoint Courseware

- ➤ It's The Law: The Legal Side of Management
 - Equal Employment & Discrimination
 - Civil Rights Act of 1964 and Its Amendments
 - Employment Discrimination
 - Types of Discrimination
 - Behavior-Based Interviewing
 - Six Steps to Progressive Discipline
 - Sexual Harassment
 - Email and Texting
 - ADA- Americans with Disabilities Act
 - Family Medical Leave Act

• Inscapes DiSC

Personal Development Profile.

• Other

- ➤ Microsoft Office Suite 2007/2010/2016-online and in class
 - Word
 - PowerPoint
 - Excel
 - Access
- ➤ Keyboarding and Document Processing-online and in class
- Career Development
- Customer Service
- Soft Skills

Classes qualified to teach:

- Introduction to Microcomputers/Introduction to Computers: Basic components of a microcomputer, terminology of computing and fundamentals of integrated software using a word processor(Word), spreadsheet (Excel), graphics(PowerPoint) and database (Access) applications. Other topics include computers in society, business, and government, as well as the Internet, jobs and careers in computing.
- Microsoft Office Suite 2010-2016-2019
- Introduction to Business/Management
- Administrative Assistant Seminar
- Administrative Assistant Management
- Internet, E-Commerce and Technology: This course covers various topics relating to competitive advantages in today's global markets. Discussion includes Internet strategies, electronic business concepts, TQM, profit implications in the leveraging of intellectual property, management adaptation to and adoption of emerging technologies.
- *Management Information Systems:* This course provides an overview of the role of information systems their management and the technology. The evolving role of information systems and related technology within a business are studied. The learning process is enhanced by using spreadsheet and database management software on personal computers for business applications.
- *Organizational Behavior*: Behavioral aspects of individual motivation, group behavior, and interactions in formal and informal organization structures.
- *Human Resource Management:* Study of the typical operations of a personnel office including determination of manpower requirements, the employment process, and the maintenance and control of the staff through wage and salary administration, insurance, safety, discipline, and employee preparation for collective bargaining.
- Business Organization and Management: Management concepts including different methods and styles needed to operate a business.
- Business English Review
- *Principles of Training and Development*: An orientation to the field of training and development in the corporate environment.
- *Current Topics in Office Administration*: Comprehensive coverage of all facets of administrative assistant responsibilities with extensive use of the internet, including travel and conference planning, time and stress management, handling incoming and outgoing communication e-mail, international business protocol. Also focuses on professional image building and career advancement.
- Computer Fundamentals: Basic instruction designed to help those who have a fear of computers become
 comfortable with basic terminology and concepts. Students examine computer jargon, hardware, software,
 computer systems and different types of computers and their uses. Covers the impact of computers on work
 and society. Some hands on experience.
- Word Processing: This course introduces the concepts of Word Processing including creating, editing, storing, retrieving and printing documents. Formatting, changing margins and tabs, using the proofing tools, and enhancing text. Students develop proficiency in creating multiple documents; create headers and footers, producing form letters and reports (MLA, Business, and APA), Proper formatting procedures for memos, tables, work cited, table of contents and title pages.
- Introduction to Windows: This course provides an introduction to and practice with basic windows skills, including the mouse techniques of clicking and dragging, and re-sizing windows. Students navigate the desktop and access and use online help, work with shortcuts; customize windows and use the windows explorer.
- Stress Management: Developing strategies for managing stressful situations through relaxation and coping techniques.
- Psychology and Business: Course examines theory and issues in organizational psychology.